A Guide to the Records of the Dean of the College, Theodorick Pryor Campbell, 1917-1924
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech
Records of the Dean of the College, Theodorick Pryor Campbell, 1917-1924
Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 11/1
4.2 Cubic Feet; 3 boxes
This collection contains records of Theodorick Pryor Campbell, the dean of the college at Virginia Tech from 1920-1924. This collection consists primarily of correspondence with faculty, educational organizations, parents, presidents Julian A. Burruss and J. D. Eggleston, students, and government entities. Subjects include advertising, budget, disciplinary matters, hazing, and land purchases. Some correspondence dates to 1917-1919 when Campbell was Dean of the Faculty.
Campbell, Theodorick Pryor, 1862-1928
Administrative Information
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Source of Acquisition
The Records of the Dean of the College, Theodorick Pryor Campbell were transferred to Special Collections and University Archives prior to 2002.
Biographical Note
Theodorick Pryor Campbell (1862-1928) worked at Virginia Tech from 1889 to 1924 as a professor of modern languages, dean of the Academic Department (1903-1905), dean of the general faculty (1914-1920), and dean of the college (1920-1924). Health issues caused Campbell to resign as dean but he continued to teach until his death in 1928.
Please note: Campbell's first name is spelled various different ways, also shortened to Theo. Theodorick is the most widely accepted spelling.
Source: Cox, Clara B. "In retrospect: Theodoric Pryor Campbell: With a name like Theodoric...", Virginia Tech Magazine, vol. 30, no. 4, Summer 2008. Accessed March 26, 2020. https://www.vtmag.vt.edu/sum08/retrospect.html.
Scope and Content
This collection consists primarily of correspondence, including letters to and from the Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools of the Southern States, Engineering Enlisted Reserve Corps, faculty, Federal Board of Vocational Education, parents, presidents Julian A. Burruss and J. D. Eggleston, students, the U.S. War Department, and the Veterans Bureau. Subjects covered in the correspondence include advertising, budget, demerits, disciplinary matters, hazing, heating plant, land purchases, letters of recommendation, Shops Department, statistics, and VPI's Army Training School. Included within some of the folders are correspondence from 1917-19 when Campbell's title was Dean of the Faculty.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically. If there are several folders of the same subject, they are then arranged by date.
Rights Statement for Archival Description
The guide to the Records of the Dean of the College, Theodorick Pryor Campbell by Special Collections and University Archives, Virginia Tech, is licensed under a CC0 (https://creativecommons.org/share-your- work/public-domain/cc0/).
Index Terms
Subjects:
University History; University Archives; Virginia Agricultural and Mechanical College and Polytechnic Institute
Contents List
- Absences, Unexcused 1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Absentees for Jan. 3rd1923 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Admissions1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Advertising1922-1924 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Applications and Appointments1921-1924 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Association of Colleges of Secondary Schools of the Southern States1917, 1919-1920 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Board of Visitors1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Burruss, Julian A., Pres, 1919-07-01-1920-07-01 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Burruss, J.A., Pres.1920-07-01-1921-07-01 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Burruss, Pres. Julian A.1921-07-1923-01 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Burruss, J.A.1923-01-01-1923-07-01 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Burruss, J.A. Statistical1920-1922 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Burruss, J.A. - Statistical Papers1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Burruss, J.A. Pres - Statistical Papers1923-01-01-1923-07-01 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Campbell, Dean T.P. - Training Detachments; Auto Mechanics 1st and 2nd1918-1919 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Committee on Education and Special Training, 1st and 2nd Detachment1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Contract, Estimates, and Vouchers - 1st and 2nd Detachment 1918 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Concrete Work 1st and 2nd Detachment1918 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Dean Campbell - Papers, Hazing1919 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Demerits - Students with Excessive Number1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Demerits1922-1923 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Demerits, Excessive1923-1924 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Disciplinary Matters1921-1923 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Eggleston, J.D.1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Eggleston, J.D., Pres1918-1919 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Engineering Enlisted Reserve Corps1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Faculty and Faculty Committees1917-1920 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Federal Board Contracts and Vouchers1919-1920 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Federal Board for Vocational Education1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Federal Board - M.C. Kibler Co-Ordinator1921-1922 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Federal Board1921 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Heating Plant - Dining Hall1915 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Karr, J.E.1916 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Miscellaneous1918 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Misc. Correspondence 1st and 2nd Detachments1918 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Probation1922-1923 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Recommendation, Letters of1921-1923 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Recommendation, Letters of 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Requests for Outside Work1921-1924 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Requisitions1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Rhodes Scholarships1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Rolls and Grades - 1st Detachment1918 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Rolls and Grades, etc. - 2nd Detachment1918 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Science Group - Comments on Reports1923-1925 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Shops Dept. 1918 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Skuse, Capt. John C. - Misc. Papers1918 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- State Students' Loan Fund1921-1924 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Students' Naval Training Corps1918-10-1918-12 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Summer School Papers and Credits1924-1925 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Summer School Pupils (State Teachers)1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Student Army Training Corps1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Veterans' Bureau1922-1923 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Veterans' Bureau1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Waiterships1923 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Waitership Applications and Appointments1924 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- War Department1919 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Wireless Construction Instructor1918-1919 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- YMCA1918 (Box 3, Folder 15)